<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meta on Bruno Scopelliti</title>
    <link>https://brunoscopelliti.com/blog/search/meta/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Meta on Bruno Scopelliti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 09:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://brunoscopelliti.com/blog/search/meta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Asynchronous font loading</title>
      <link>https://brunoscopelliti.com/blog/asynchronous-font-loading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brunoscopelliti.com/blog/asynchronous-font-loading/</guid>
      <description>The characters you&amp;rsquo;re reading right now are rendered in a font called Ubuntu. It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty populare one. I&amp;rsquo;m also using the Merriweather font, in the homepage, right under my face, and in a few other places. Aren&amp;rsquo;t they nice? Hardly not!
However fonts are generally heavy resources to load&amp;hellip; and having to load more of them may negatively affect loading performance of a website. In particular, there are two different problems:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I ported my blog to HTTPS</title>
      <link>https://brunoscopelliti.com/blog/how-i-ported-my-blog-to-https/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brunoscopelliti.com/blog/how-i-ported-my-blog-to-https/</guid>
      <description>In the last couple of years several elements are pushing for a widespread adoption of the HTTPS protocol.
Security. Of course security, what else would you expect from HTTPS. HTTPS is all about security! It guarantees that the server you&amp;rsquo;re connecting is really the one you believe it is, and that the contents of the communications is private, so that it can&amp;rsquo;t be read, or modified by a anyone else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye WordPress 👋</title>
      <link>https://brunoscopelliti.com/blog/goodbye-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2015 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brunoscopelliti.com/blog/goodbye-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>During last year blogging has fallen down in my list of priorities.
One of my resolutions for this new year is to try to start blogging again on a regular schedule.
Even if I am a huge fan of WordPress, I have to admit that it carries with it a lot of overhead, probably not justified for a blog like my own. So I decided to give a try to jekyll, and damn, it was love at first sight 🤩</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog re-style (&#43; bonus: three WordPress tricks)</title>
      <link>https://brunoscopelliti.com/blog/blog-re-style-bonus-three-wordpress-tricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2013 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://brunoscopelliti.com/blog/blog-re-style-bonus-three-wordpress-tricks/</guid>
      <description>Some weekends ago, I saved few of my free time to work on my blog.
The most evident change is that now for my blog, I&amp;rsquo;m using the Ryu theme, by the guys of Automattic.
It had been a long time since the last time I had worked with WordPress, and I really appreciated it. So today I want to share three useful tricks to customize your WordPress implementation.
One of the characteristics of this blog even before the restyle, was that, even if you are logged in WordPress, the top toolbar is not displayed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
